<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AMM on The Terminal</title><link>https://laxman.tech/tags/amm/</link><description>Recent content in AMM on The Terminal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 02:19:43 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://laxman.tech/tags/amm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Marka: American Fractional Reserve System on Solana</title><link>https://laxman.tech/posts/american-fractinal-reserve-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 02:19:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://laxman.tech/posts/american-fractinal-reserve-system/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="https://media.bizj.us/view/img/1120091/bank-vault-thinkstock*750xx2807-1579-0-222.jpg"/>
&lt;h2 id="implimentation-of-american-fractional-reserve-system-in-solana">
Implimentation of American Fractional Reserve System in Solana
&lt;a href="#implimentation-of-american-fractional-reserve-system-in-solana" class="h-anchor" aria-hidden="true">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Blog and Code in production :)&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="history">
History
&lt;a href="#history" class="h-anchor" aria-hidden="true">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Modeled in 1660s, Fractional reserve banking lead to the invention of paper money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A economic institution of the government initialised to manage the total supply of U.S Dollars
which includes creation of fresh money too [not minting].&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>There are blockchain protocols building under FRB system but not preferred. Since, the fluctuations can cause adverseral damage to ones collateral unless its a &lt;em>stablecoin&lt;/em>. But core reason of Marka is to understand the mathematical indications and reservational transactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet">&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr">A fractional reserve banking scheme on top of bitcoin just means you are short bitcoin. A bitcoin bull run will severely test this, because unlike primitive govt money, bitcoin has no central bank to bail you out.&lt;br>&lt;br>Good luck! &lt;a href="https://t.co/Ou7KXfn3Mq">pic.twitter.com/Ou7KXfn3Mq&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&amp;mdash; Saifedean.com (@saifedean) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/saifedean/status/1296074308301791236?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 19, 2020&lt;/a>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8">&lt;/script>
&lt;h3 id="what-is-frb">
What is FRB
&lt;a href="#what-is-frb" class="h-anchor" aria-hidden="true">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the paper world, a central bank institutionalised by the government has the authority to print money. Pulled into circulation via bonds or securities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Consider a commercial/private under which the sellers deposit the paper money. The bank follows &lt;em>Fractional Feserve Lending&lt;/em> [FRL] where it keeps only fraction of the reserve and lends the rest to other business/people as loans, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If Alice deposits $10 into Bank A at a reserve rate of 10% the bank lends the rest of the money, that is $9 to Bob who inturn deposits it into Bank B which reserves a fraction (3%) and lends the remaining $8.73 of into Clara depositing it into Bank C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The system now has escalated into a total amount of $27.73 from $10. This is knows as the &lt;em>Money Multiplier Theory&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The money multiplier measures the maximum amount of money that commercial banks can create by a given unit of central bank money. In other words, the total amount of loans that commercial banks are allowed to extend is a multiple of the reserves and this multiple is the inverse of the reserve ratio.
&amp;mdash; Injective Labs&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>One important requirement of this system in Cryptoworld is that there is no legal protection for crypto assets, pulling a backup from governance/Foundations/operators requires following a nested requirments which is not immediate and takes quite a while to bring into action. Where as with reserves, an automated balance is maintained.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="markahttpsgithubcommarka-protocolmarka">
&lt;a href="https://github.com/Marka-protocol/marka">Marka&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="#markahttpsgithubcommarka-protocolmarka" class="h-anchor" aria-hidden="true">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Introducing &lt;a href="https://github.com/Marka-protocol/marka">&lt;em>Marka&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, a dAPP designed as a replication of Fractional Lending (and Borrowing) system including reserve ratios, treasuries [vault] and multiplier effect or yield aggregation. Marka will be open source and public while mapping each progresion into this blog post on a motto that the end result has to be top notch. May it be a program that adds 2 numbers or intersects two chain gotta show standards&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scaffolding and Architecture [4 hours]&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>